# Rachel Rigdon

**United States** 



rmrigdon@gmail.com



(903) 390-1752



linkedin.com/in/rachel-rigdon

## **Summary**

I'm a curious and fast learner who pairs deep product knowledge with empathy for the user. I work closely with product and engineering teams to coordinate feature documentation and releases.

I've worked as both a solo tech writer and a team lead producing software documentation for government agencies, start-ups, and large-scale enterprises. I excel at creating and training technical processes, including managing the docs-as-code systems used by 10+ writers to support 11+ help sites.

## **Experience**

#### Lead Technical Writer

SailPoint

Jul 2022 - Present (11 months)

- Collaborate with engineering and product teams to track feature developments and align releases
- Train and support 10+ writers in creating and maintaining 9+ help websites
- Create information architecture, site configurations, and build and deployment pipelines Mentor teammates to encourage a culture of grace and empathy

#### Senior Technical Writer

SailPoint

Feb 2020 - Jul 2022 (2 years 6 months)

- Led the transition of SaaS documentation to new technical tooling including MkDocs, Markdown, MkDocs-Material, VS Code, GitHub, Google Analytics, and Google Tag Manager
- Architected and launched public-facing documentation for two new Cloud Governance SaaS products, leading to being nominated for the New Crew award twice for exceptional contributions to the company

## Technical Writer

Anaconda, Inc.

Dec 2018 - Jan 2020 (1 year 2 months)

- Maintained online release notes, installation guides, tutorials, troubleshooting, concepts, and FAQs for open-source products used by 20+ million users
- Collaborated with subject matter experts, including engineers, community members, product managers, and trainers, to ensure accuracy and clarity Created documentation using Sphinx, ReStructuredText, Read the Docs, Visual Studio Code, and GitHub

#### ■ Technical Writer

DISCO

Jul 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 5 months)

- Managed feature process documentation in Confluence spaces, workflows, and Jira projects
- Developed a scalable means of publishing and sharing documentation across the organization

- Worked with developers, product managers, and UX designers to record technical processes and feature development arcs

## Adjunct Professor of Communication Studies

Southwestern University

Sep 2015 - Dec 2016 (1 year 4 months)

I created the curriculum and taught:

- Public Speaking and Civic Engagement
- Business and Professional Speaking
- Communication, Culture, and Social Justice

## **Education**



## Northwestern University

Master of Arts, Rhetoric and Public Culture 2010 - 2012

## Southwestern University

Bachelor of Arts, English Language and Literature, General 2005 - 2009 Specialty in Rhetoric and Composition Minor in Communication Studies

#### **Skills**

content management · documentation · editing · information architecture · mentoring · public speaking · Google Analytics · Software Documentation · Git · Project Management